Remember...
牢記
Why did he kill them? Who are they?
兇手為什麼殺死他們？他們是誰？
They have 80 priors between them.
這三人一共有80個前科
They're not connected to Kambura, though. No fingerprints, either.
這些人與坎佈拉冇有聯係，而且也冇有發現任何指紋
But CCTV caught the crime.
但是監控拍到了嫌疑人
Let me guess. Cat costume.
我猜他穿了貓服裝
Here's your mafia.
這就是黑手黨的下場
PERSONAL
個人
TONIGHT, A STAR FELL FROM THE SKY
今晚，一顆流星劃過天空
I MADE A WISH
我許了一個願望
One day, when I was on night duty, a man came to see me.
有一天，當我在夜班時，一個男人來找我
I remember every word he said to me.
我記得他對我說的每句話
"You're going to forget about what happened."
“你會忘記發生了什麼事”
"Or you'll disappear," he said.
他說：“否則你會消失的  ”
Hamza Kaymak, right?
哈姆薩·凱馬克，對嗎？
His photos will be everywhere in half an hour.
他的照片將在半小時內隨處可見
Hamza is going to tell them everything he knows. It can't be helped.
哈姆薩會告訴他們他所知道的一切，冇辦法了
You're going to tell them what you know as well, Vural.
你也要告訴他們你知道什麼，烏拉爾
Without forgetting about Ufuk.
不要忘了烏福克
Take a seat, Vural.
坐下，烏拉爾
Hello again.
再次問好
You told me to come see you if I needed anything.
你告訴我如果我有需要時就去找你
Would you kindly die for me?
你願意為我去死嗎？
Firuz, this won't get me in trouble, right?
菲魯茲，這不會給我帶來麻煩吧？
What did you find?
你發現了什麼？
I found some blood on the crime scene that didn't belong to the victim.
我在犯罪現場發現了一些不屬於受害者的血跡
It probably belongs to the killer.
可能屬於殺手
- Is this the DNA report? - Yes.
-這是DNA報告嗎？-是的
You think being involved with my daughter makes you immortal?
你以為和我女兒在一起就能讓你永生嗎？
If I'm not spilling your blood for now,
如果我暫時不殺你
who would you like to take your place?
你想讓誰代替你去死？
How about your blood brother?
你該死的兄弟怎麼樣？
That works, right? That works beautifully.
那行得通，對嗎？那行得通
Isn't that the corpse from the forest?
那不是森林裏的屍體嗎？
Reply to them. Let's see who they are.
回複他們  讓我們看看這些人是誰
You know what I wished for?
你知道我許了什麼願望嗎？
To be a good person.
做個好人
But...
但……
She remembers everything.
她記得一切
Good morning to you, Agah.
早上好，阿加
No killing anyone today, deal?
今天不殺人，對不對？
Today, we're going to go...
今天，我們要去……
We're going to watch Cemil's show...
我們要去看塞米爾的錶演
No off-hours work today.
今天冇有下班時間
And we're going to see Feza.
我們要去看望費紮
No, that's tomorrow.
不，那是明天
Fine. Sure.
當然  可以
Sure.
當然
Feza is tomorrow.
費紮是明天
Yes.
是
Sleep, wake, visit Feza.
睡覺，醒來，拜訪費紮
GOOD MORNING DEVA. I'M GOING OUT.
早上好德瓦  我出門了
EAT SOMETHING BEFORE YOU LEAVE FOR SCHOOL.
在去學校之前記得吃東西
No, don't do it.
不，不要這樣做
Go get a seat on the front row.
去前排找個座位
You ready?
你準備好了嗎？
Go on, shoot. The last one was pure luck. Come on!
繼續射門，剛才純屬幸運！
I was a goalie for many years. I even played for FC Sishane.
我做了多年守門員，曾經為西甲聯賽效力
- I'm shooting the ball. - Go on.
-我要射門了  -來吧
- Goal! - Out!
-進球了！-射偏了！
- How's that out! - That was a goal. You need glasses!
-怎麼是射偏了！-那裏算進球的，你需要戴眼鏡了！
No, the post is from here to there. That was out!
不，球門是從這裏到那裏的！剛剛那球出界了
Son! How many times have I told you not to play soccer here?
孩子！我告訴過你多少次不要在這裏踢足球？
Take your ball and play somewhere else!
帶上你的球去別的地方玩！
He's right. So disrespectful!
他說的冇錯！一點不尊重人！
- You can't play soccer here! - That was a goal!
-你不能在這裏踢足球  -那是一個進球
- That was a goal! - Like hell it was. It was out.
-那是一個進球！-進球才怪  明明是界外球
- Dad? - Zuhal? I didn't realize you were here.
-爸爸？-祖哈爾？我冇看到你在這裏
I came with Cemil.
我和塞米爾一起來的
- Did you know Tayfun? - Of course. Back from Kambura.
-你認識泰豐嗎  -當然認識  是我在坎佈拉的老朋友
Cemil was devastated, dad. He's grief-stricken.
爸爸  塞米爾收到了重創  他悲痛欲絕
- I can imagine. - He's devastated.
-我能想象到  -他被毀了
I can imagine. They were like brothers.
我能想象到  他們就像兄弟一樣
- I should go give my condolences. - Alright. I'll see you at home tonight.
-我應該去哀悼了  -好吧，今晚在家見
- You still remember how to get home? - Do you?
-還記得怎麼回家嗎？  -你呢？
The ballistics report came today.
彈道報告今天出來了
The bastard blew up the greenhouse using a timed C4 blast.
兇手用定時的C4炸藥炸毀了溫室
Not a simple C4. A timed one!
不是一個簡單的C4炸彈   是個定時炸彈！
He has an armory or something. He could start a war tomorrow.
他有軍械庫還是什麼，完全可以發動戰爭了
I have something else to tell you.
我還有事要告訴你
I was in a meeting today.
我今天開會時
The prosecutor general and the police commissioner wanted me to pay a visit.
總檢察長和警察局長想讓我去拜訪他們
Unless I make an arrest within one week, we're done.
除非我在一個星期內將其逮捕，否則我們就廢了
I'll be the first to go.
我將是第一個離開的
Then, just so you don't get offended, you two will be fired as well.
然後，就這樣，冇有冒犯的意思，你們兩個也會被解雇
This is our last shot.
這是我們的最後的機會了
We have to find something.
我們必須找到一些蛛絲馬跡
If we can't, they'll boot us and bring in someone who can.
如果我們做不到，他們會讓我們滾蛋然後換個能人
I should ask you if that's clear, but you're pretty bright, so no need.
我應該問你是否清楚，但是你們都很聰明，所以冇必要問了
CEM?L HAVRAN  KAMBURANS FOUNDATION
塞米爾·哈夫蘭 坎佈拉基金會
Easy.
別急
My condolences...
節哀順變
- Oh dear Cemil, my condolences... - Agah...
-親愛的塞米爾，節哀  -阿加
What am I to do now?
我現在該怎麼辦？
He was such an angel.
他真是個好人
- Come stand by me. - Stay strong, son. Stay strong.
-一直支援我  -堅強起來，孩子
- Thanks. - Can't stand against fate.
-謝謝  -不能抗拒命運
- Thank you. - I told him so many times.
-謝謝 -我跟他說了很多遍了
What are you doing, running greenhouses in the middle of nowhere?
你在做什麼，在茫茫荒野中開溫室？
- Come on, work with me. - Thank you.
-來吧，和我一起工作  -謝謝
I begged him to accept, but he wouldn't. Money meant nothing to him.
我求他來我公司  但他不來  金錢對他冇有任何意義
Such a dirty world we live in.
我們生活在一個如此骯髒的世界
Stay strong, son. Can't stand against fate.
堅強，孩子  不能抗拒命運
What fate?
什麼命運？
They blew up a florist using a bomb.
他們用炸彈炸毀了一家花店
- Thank you. - You see that casket? It's empty.
-謝謝-看到棺材了嗎？是空的
They couldn't find his corpse. It was blown to bits.
他們找不到他的屍體
Get a hold of yourself, Cemil. Whoever did it is bound to get caught.
控製住你自己，塞米爾  不管是誰幹的，兇手一定會被抓住
No. No...
不，不
I'll find him. And when I do, that son of a bitch will...
我會找到他的，當我找到他時，一定把那孫子……
Hush! Cemil, we're in a mosque. Don't sin.
噓！塞米爾，我們在清真寺裏，別說了
Agah...
阿加
That bastard stabbed me in the heart.
那個混蛋刺傷了我的心
- How did you know the departed? - He was a good man.
-你怎麼認識死者的？-他是個好人
-你怎麼知道死者的？-他是個好人
- Do you give him your blessing? - We do.
-祝福他了嗎?  -祝福他
Al-Fatiha!
天父！
This girl,
這個女孩
the girl Tayyar raped...
塔亞爾強姦的……女孩
What are you thinking?
你在想什麼？
What did Vural say?
烏拉爾怎麼說？
The fireman, what was his name? Halis.
消防員，他叫什麼名字？哈裏斯
- He's dead, right? - Yes?
-他死了吧？-是嗎？
- He knew about what happened. - If Vural's telling the truth. Yes.
-他知道發生了什麼  -如果烏拉爾說的是真的
So Halis tampered with the report to protect Ufuk.
因此，哈裏斯篡改了這份報告，以保護烏福克
So he knew about the girl. Ufuk must've told him.
那麼他知道那個女孩  烏福克一定告訴過他
I'm wracking my brain...
我在想……
Ufuk came to us of his own volition. He wanted to tell us everything.
烏福克自願來這裏，告訴我們一切
- Why didn't he ever mention that girl? - You saw how he was.
-他為什麼不提那個女孩？-你也看到他了
How can we know what's going through Ufuk's mind?
我們怎麼知道烏夫克在想什麼？
Anyway. Let's get back to how Halis knows about the girl.
無論如何，讓我們回到哈裏斯對女孩了解的話題
Either Ufuk told him, or he'd heard it somewhere else.
烏福克告訴了他，或者他在其他地方聽說了
- Kambura is a small place, after all. - Yes...
-畢竟坎佈拉是個小地方  -是的
Alright.
好的
If Halis knew...
如果哈裏斯知道
Why wouldn't anyone else know?
為什麼別人都不知道？
What if they...
如果他們……
What if
如果
they all knew about the rape,
他們都知道強奸，
but didn't say or do anything?
但什麼都冇說也什麼都冇做？
The girl is speaking to me. See what she's saying?
這個女孩在跟我說話  看到她說什麼了嗎？
Save me, Nevra.
內芙拉，救救我
I MET A GIRL TODAY HER NAME IS NEVRA YILMAZ
我今天遇到一個女孩  她叫內芙拉·艾爾瑪斯
I TRUST ONLY HER BECAUSE NEVRA GETS ME
我隻相信她  因為內芙拉了解我
She's been speaking to me through him this whole time.
她一直都在和我說話
All of it.
所有這些都是對我說的
So Tayyar...
那麼塔亞爾……
Raped this girl. He raped her ten years ago.
強奸了這個女孩  他十年前強奸了她
He threatened and scared her somehow.
他以某種方式威脅並恐嚇她
She didn't want to come forward.
她不想挺身而出
So all these murders are revenge for that girl.
所以所有這些謀殺都是為女孩複仇
If we find the girl, we will have found him.
如果我們找到那個女孩，我們將會找到他
Whoever's committing the murders is someone who knows the girl.
兇手一定認識這個女孩
Just as Ufuk killed the rapist...
就像烏福克殺死了強奸犯一樣……
He's killing all the people who stood by and did nothing.
他正在殺所有袖手旁觀的人
- So they're the silent perpetrators. - Exactly. Exactly.
-所以他們是沈默的肇事者  -正是這樣
We need to find her. We should go to Kambura immediately.
我們需要找到她  我們應該立即去坎佈拉
And do what?
做什麼呢？
Get on the PA system and ask the whole town whom Tayyar raped?
用廣播喇叭問所有人塔亞爾強奸了誰？
No, not like that.
不，不是那樣
But if we assume that she was a young girl ten years ago,
但是如果我們假設她十年前是個年輕女孩，
I'm going to gather all women between the ages of 25 and 50
那麼我將所有25至50歲之間的女性整理出來
in the county and talk to them.
在村子裏和她們談談
Do you think it will work?
你認為這行得通嗎？
Do you have any other suggestions?
你有什麼其他的建議？
Agah? Agah!
阿加？阿加？
Taci?
塔奇？
I thought I knew you when I saw you at a distance.
我在遠處看到你時就覺得是你
- Years go by so fast, huh, Agah? - Yes. They do.
-歲月流逝太快了  -是的
Do you have some time? Let's go sit somewhere.
你有時間嗎  我們去別的地方
- No, I wasn't going to... - Wasn't going to what?
-不，我不打算……  -不打算做什麼？
- I have an appointment. - With whom?
-我有個約會  -和誰約會？
With myself.
和我自己
Come on. I've found you again after all these years.
來吧，過了這麼多年我們又見麵了
I'm not letting go. I'm having a terrible day as it is.
我不放你走  我今天過得很糟糕
It's about Tayfun... He was so young.
泰豐……他還很年輕
- Cemil's devastated, of course. - I know. Devastated, yes.
-當然  對塞米爾是毀滅性的打擊  -是的，毀滅性
Curse the bastard that did it!
詛咒那個兇手不得好死
Come on, don't play hard to get. We can take my car.
來吧，別裝了 坐我的車走
My car's right over there. Son, bring my car over.
我的車就在那邊  孩子，把我的車開過來
- Sure, if you really want to. - Let's go.
-當然可以，如果你想開車的話  -我們走吧
- When one's time has come... - Excuse me?
-當一個人的時間到了……  -什麼？
My bag's in the car. I should go fetch it.
我的包在車裏，我應該去拿一下
Deren Koro?lu...
德仁·科羅魯
I MET A GIRL TODAY
我今天遇到一個女孩
As the founding members of the Dog Slayer Fan Club...
作為狗殺手粉絲俱樂部的初始成員
We formally accept you into our ranks.
我們正式接受你加入我們
Welcome, all of you.
歡迎大家
Keeping true to tradition, we're going to celebrate
秉承古早，我們將要和
with some Dog Slayer.
狗殺手一起慶祝
A few Dog Slayers, in fact.
實際上，有一些狗殺手
- Arda, right? - Yes.
-阿爾達，對嗎？-是
It's really strange...
真的很奇怪
It's a really weird coincidence.
這真是一個奇怪的巧合
You're strolling through the forest, looking to take some footage.
你正在森林中漫步，希望拍攝一些照片素材
And what do you know, you run into a corpse.
但世事難料，遇到了一具屍體
That's exactly what happened. We were really surprised, as well.
就是這樣  我們也很驚訝
It's really hard to get hold of a body.
真的很難控製身體
- We found one hanging from a tree. - They apparently grow on trees, right?
-我們在樹上發現了一個懸吊物  -它們顯然長在樹上，對嗎？
Alright, then.
那好吧
Cheers to Dog Slayer.
敬狗殺手
So? What do we do now?
那我們現在做什麼？
Art.
藝術
- What's this? - Tomorrow's article.
-這是什麼？-明天的文章
You think this is why I called you over?
你以為這就是我給你打電話的原因嗎？
I have something else to ask you.
我還有事要問你
Like what?
什麼問題？
Like are you alright?
類似你還好嗎？
I'm fine, thank you.
我很好，謝謝你
We can cover you if you need some vacation time.
如果你需要一些休假時間，包在我們身上
No...
不用
I'm serious. We're doing alright.
我是認真的  我們現在很好
The tourism agencies keep calling us, asking us to send someone on vacation.
旅行社不斷打電話給我們，要我們派人去渡假
It's advertising for them. You can take a few days off.
這是他們的廣告  你可以休息幾天
Take in the sights, have some delicious food.
參觀景點，吃點美味的食物
And when you come back, write about it.
當你回來時，寫篇文章
It will do you good, won't it?
這對你有好處，不是嗎？
- I'm already good. - You're already good? Are you now?
-我已經很好了  -你已經很好了嗎？
What's this then?
那這是什麼？
What's this you wrote?
你寫的是什麼？
Look at this.
看這個
Fake fire brigade reports.
假消防隊報告
Fake health bills.
假醫療賬單
Heavy penal court judges taking bribes.
重刑法院法官受賄
And that's not the half of it. It goes on and on.
而且這隻是一小部分，冇完冇了
I'll read out some. Where was that?
我讀一些給你聽  在哪裏？
Here.
這裏
Listen.
聽
"Perhaps, including the civilian administrative chief,"
“也許包括平民行政首長”
every single prominent person in the county knew about the incident.
縣裏每個著名人物都知道這件事
Which is why this doesn't concern only Kambura.
這就是為什麼這不僅僅與坎佈拉有關
If there is a crime,
如果真的有犯罪
and if that crime was whitewashed,
如果該罪行被粉飾，
this concerns the whole country.
這就關係到整個國家
And if that crime is the killing of a family of seven in a fire,
如果那個罪行是殺死7口之家，
"we were all burned in that fire. We just don't realize it."
“那麼我們都被那場大火燒死了，我們隻是冇有意識到”
What happened to you, son?
孩子  你怎麼了
What do you mean? I'm doing my job.
什麼意思？  我在做我的工作
- You used to write such pretty things. - Yes.
-你以前寫過很漂亮的文章-是的
I used to write about shit that didn't matter.
我以前經常寫無所謂的垃圾文
Listen, Ates. I can't publish this article.
聽著，阿提斯  我無法發錶這篇文章
I know what will happen to me if I chose to publish this article.
我知道如果我選擇發錶這篇文章將會對我産生什麼影響
I'll get 40 phone calls within the minute.
我一分鍾會接到40個電話
Forgive me, but I don't have time for that.
原諒我，但我冇有時間接
Then...
那麼……
You forgive me as well.
也請原諒我
Look, Ates...
聽好，阿提斯
I'll put it in terms you'll understand.
我會用你能理解的語言來錶達
If you insist on getting this article published,
如果你堅持讓這篇文章發錶，
you can no longer work for this paper. You got that?
你就不能在這家報社工作了  你明白了？
I never worked for this paper.
我從未為這家報社工作
I'm just now starting to work here. I haven't done any real work in years.
我現在才剛剛開始  我多年來從冇有做過任何真正意義上的工作
But we're not in the same industry.
但是我們不在同一個行業
That's why I bid you good luck...
這就是為什麼我要祝你好運
- And lots of profit!  - Ates! Ates!
-祝公司能賺很多錢！-阿提斯！阿提斯！
Ates, get back here!
阿提斯  回來！
Enjoy your day, guys.
祝大家玩的開心
- Hello? - Hello?
-餵？-餵？
- Nevra, I just resigned. - Congratulations. How does it feel?
-內芙拉，我剛辭職了 -恭喜，你的感覺如何？
Like I'm myself.
感覺像我自己
I'm feeling like myself for the first time in a long while.
很長時間以來第一次感覺像自己
I'm happy to hear that.
我很高興聽到這個消息
- Can I call you back later? - Sure.
-我可以等下再打給你嗎？-當然可以
Finally!
終於！
It will do you good, Ates!
這對你有好處，阿提斯！
We sent word to every house. But some of them are at work,
我們嚮每戶人家都傳達了消息  但是有些人在上班
- All the others are inside. - Alright. Thank you.
-其他人都在裏麵  -好，謝謝
- Did you put the board up? - Yes.
-你把闆子放好了嗎-是的
All you're achieving right now is scaring those people, and that's it.
你現在所做的就是嚇唬那些人，僅此而已
Ladies. We'll ask the men to leave.
女士們，我們請男人們離開
They'll leave us alone in here. Woman to woman.
他們會出去  我們來談談
- But I'd like to... - We'll be fast. Don't worry.
-但我想……-我們會很快的  別擔心
Come on, let's have some tea together. I'm buying. Come on.
來吧，讓我們一起喝杯茶吧
My name is Nevra. Nevra Y?lmaz.
我是內芙拉·艾爾瑪斯
We know who you are. We've been watching you on TV.
我們知道你是誰  電視上看到過你
Good. Good.
很好
Then you also should know that I lived here for a short while.
那你們也應該知道我在這裏住過一陣
You could say I'm a Kamburan, in a way.
也可以說我是一個坎佈蘭人
I'd like you to share
我希望你們能夠
everything I say here today with your friends at home.
把我今天說的話和你們的家人及朋友分享
- Is that a deal? - Sure, we'll tell them.
-可以嗎？-當然，我們會告訴他們
But I have food cooking at home. Whatever it is, make it quick.
但是我家裏煮著飯，不管你要說什麼，快點說
I'd like you to take out your phones and save this number to your contacts.
我希望你拿出手機並將此號碼保存到你的聯係人中
You can call this number 24/7, whenever you want.
你隨時可以撥打此號碼
Go on.
繼續
We have food cooking at home. We wouldn't want them to get burnt.
我們家裏還煮著飯，我們不想讓它燒糊
Do you have it? Save it as Nevra the Cop.
保存了嗎？保存為內芙拉警察
Ladies...
女士們
Today, or yesterday, or a year ago...
今天或昨天或一年前
Or some day in the past, no matter when.
或過去的某一天，無論何時
If you've been harassed or raped, please call this number.
如果你遭到騷擾或強奸，請撥打此電話
I'll be the only one who answers the phone,
我將是唯一接聽電話的人，
and I'll be the only one who'll know who's called.
我將是唯一知道你名字的人
I give you my word as a woman.
我以女性的身份嚮您保證
What if they do call? What will you do about it?
如果他們打來電話怎麼辦？你會怎麼做？
Whatever the caller wants me to.
來電者想要我做什麼
Not more, not less.
我就做什麼
Are you sick? Caught a cold or something?
你生病了？感冒了？
Yes. I'll tell you about it some time.
是的，我等下會告訴你的
- So? You live here now? - Yeah.
-那麼  你現在住在這裏嗎？-是的
No more home.
冇別的家了
This is my home.
這就是我的家
Isn't it hard?
不難嗎？
Sometimes, sure.
有時候是的
But it's automatic. Everything here's automatic.
但這是自動的  一切都是自動的
Automatic...
自動……
Press a button, and it goes. Press a button, and it stops.
按下一個按鈕它就走，再按一個就停下
The boys keep asking me...
孩子們經常會問我
"Dad, what do you do all alone out at sea?"
“爸爸，你一個人住在海上幹什麼？”
They're concerned. Concerned that I might die.
他們擔心我可能會死
- I'm sick of people. - You don't say.
-我討厭別人  -還用說
What?
什麼？
You used to want people around all the time. Didn't you?
你過去身邊總是有人，不是嗎？
You would ask us to picnic on weekends. You wouldn't let it go.
你會邀請我們周末去野餐  你不會放過任何機會
I did. It's been so long.
是的  已經很久了
I'm so old now, Agah.
我很老了，??阿加
I learned only one thing in this life.
我這輩子隻學了一件事
You know what that is?
你知道那是什麼嗎？
Keep away from people.
遠離人
Yeah? Why?
是嗎？為什麼？
Either they'll hurt you, or you'll hurt them.
他們會傷害你，或者你會傷害他們
Two people coming together is like smashing two eggs together.
兩個人在一起就像兩個雞蛋互砸一樣
One of them is bound to get smashed.
其中之一勢必將粉碎
You know why I wanted to talk to you today, Agah?
你知道為什麼我今天想和你聊聊嗎？阿加？
- You know the killer? - What killer?
-你知道殺手嗎？-什麼殺手？
The one who killed Tayfun.
殺死泰豐的人
He shot lots of people around here, as well.
他也在這附近殺了很多人
I overheard them talking at the funeral.
我聽見他們在葬禮上討論
That's when I was reminded of it. That's also when I ran into you.
那時我想起來了，也就是我遇見你的那一刻
You worked at courthouses for years. You must still have some connections.
你在法院工作了多年  你一定還保持聯係
People with priors. Ex-prisoners. I thought maybe...
有前科的人  進過監獄的人 我想可能……
Maybe what, Taci?
也許什麼，塔奇 ？
Could you find me a killer, Agah?
也許你能為我找出殺手，阿加
Excuse me?
什麼？
A killer.
殺手
For you.
為你
What do you mean, they gathered up the women? What does she want?
什麼意思，聚集了這些女人？她想要什麼？
She's supposedly going to find the girl that Tayyar raped.
據說她要找到塔亞爾強奸的那個女孩
Oh God!
天啊！
Alright, you hold tight. I'll think of something.
好吧，你穩住  我想想辦法
Are they gone now? Nevra and the others?
他們現在走了嗎？內芙拉他們？
They're gone. They stopped by the burnt-down house.
他們走了  又去被燒毀的房子了
Took some more photos.
拍了一些照片
What are they looking for at that house?
他們在那房子找什麼？
Vural...
烏拉爾……
Tear it down.
拆了它
Get a bulldozer today. Tear the house down.
今天就買一輛推土機  把房子推了
Bury the rubble.
碎磚瓦都埋起來
I don't want them getting anything out of that house.
我不想讓他們從那所房子裏得到任何東西
Level the place. You got that?
把那房子夷為平地  明白了嗎？
Of course.
明白
Forgive me, Zuhal.
原諒我，祖哈爾
They come to me with the most ridiculous questions.
他們找我問一個愚蠢的問題
You know how I feel sometimes?
你知道有時候我是什麼感覺嗎？
As though they loaded the whole world on my back,
仿佛他們把整個世界都壓在我的背上，
and they keep telling me to get a move on.
並且不斷讓我繼續前進
Throw off your burden, then. Throw it off and be free.
那麼，甩掉你的負擔吧  扔掉它，重獲自由
How am I supposed to do that? I live in that world also.
我應該怎麼做？我還生活在那個世界裏
Fine. Leave some of it for me, then. Let me carry some of it.
好吧  負擔也給我一些，我們一起背
You're already carrying me. That's more than enough.
你已經在背負我了  那已經足夠了
I get it now.
我明白了
You get what?
明白什麼了？
Why my dad loves you so much.
為什麼我爸爸這麼愛你
So?
怎麼？
You're going to die, huh?
你快死了吧？
I'm going to die, alright...
是的  我快死了……
But it's proving to be very painful.
但事實證明，這是非常痛苦的
It's a prick of an illness.
這是一種疾病
It's seen predominantly in Turkish people.
主要出現在土耳其人身上
I wonder why.
我想知道為什麼
There are these pockets of air in the lungs.
肺裏有這些空氣囊
Little stones form inside them. Like grains of sand.
裏麵會形成沙粒一樣的結石
What's it called?
什麼病？
Alveolar Microlithiasis.
肺泡微結石癥
I see.
知道了
It's seen in Turkish people, but the name's not in Turkish.
是在土耳其人身上發現的  但是卻不是以土耳其語命名
Yes. Well...
是的
That's why, Agah... I want to die.
這就是為什麼，阿加，我想死
I can't take it anymore.
我受不了了
I have my wits about me still.
我還算有點理智
My arms and legs still work. I want to go while I still have all that.
我的胳膊和腿也還能用  我想在我仍然能自理的時候離開
I can't kill myself.
我不能自殺
I tried. I tried time and again.
我試過一次又一次
But life grabs you so tightly that it's impossible to get free.
但是生活緊緊地抓住了你，以至於無法獲得自由
Life... Wraps itself around your neck.
生活環繞在你的脖子上
I'd like someone to come...
我希望有人……
Put a bullet in my spine, and set me free.
把子彈打在我的脊椎上，讓我自由
You're right...
你是對的……
I always loved this side of yours.
我一直喜歡你這點
You used to say that if you studied law, you would want to become
你曾經說過，如果你學習法律
neither prosecutor, nor judge, nor lawyer.
你既不想做檢察官，也不想做法官或律師
- I'd like to become a notary. - Yes!
-我想當公證人-是的！
Being a notary is perfect for you.
做公證人對你來說簡直完美
This is what being a notary is like. A notary doesn't ask questions.
公證人就是這樣  公證人不問問題
He doesn't judge you...
他不審判你
He bears witness, puts down his seal, then turns around and leaves.
公證，蓋章，然後轉身離開
So, Agah?
所以  阿加？
Is there someone who'd kill me? Could you find me someone?
有冇有人願意殺我的？你能找到這個人嗎？
How are you doing?
你好嗎？
You can imagine.
你可以想象
Any news?
有什麼消息嗎？
- No. - What do you mean, no?
-冇有  -你是什麼意思，冇有？
Not one fucking change.
冇有一點改變
They made a mistake with the list.
他們把清單弄錯了
The heart was compatible with someone else.
心髒不匹配
Alright. Fine.
好吧
How's the little Sefa doing?
小塞法過得好嗎？
As you can see. He's tired. Sleeping.
如你所見  他睡著了
I didn't want to wake him up.
我不想叫醒他
Good. Good.
好
- It was so funny the other day. - What was?
-前幾天真有趣  -怎麼了？
The boys at the station were having a ball.
局裏的男孩們正在打球
Come on, not you!
不是吧！
What do you mean, "around 5.11 in height"?
你是什麼意思，“身高1米56”？
Not 6 feet. 5.11.
不是1米83  而是1米56
I could tell from your voice.
我能從你的聲音中聽出來
You were in a panic for letting him get a way.
你因他得逞而驚慌失措
How could I not be? It happened again after all these years.
怎麼會不驚慌  這麼多年之後情景重現
It says 5.11 in his report.
他的報告中說1米56
Not around 5.11, 5.11 exactly.
不是大約1米56  而是正好1米56
But I was more concerned about your situation.
但我更擔心你的情況
"I let him get away again," I thought. "There has to be someone helping him."
“我讓他又逃走了，”我想  “肯定有人在幫他  ”
Another gunfight will break out. Shots will be fired yet again.
另一場槍戰即將爆發  槍聲會再次響起
I was terrified.
我嚇壞了
- I sometimes wish you'd left me there. - Stop talking nonsense.
-有時候我希望你把我留在那裏-別胡說八道
I'm serious.
我是認真的
I wish you'd leave me there so I could fucking die.
我希望你能把我留在那裏，這樣我就可以死掉了
You jumped into the fray.
你跳入了睏境
I was out of bullets. They were about to put one in my head.
我冇子彈了  他們就要開槍打我的時候
You arrived just like Superman.
你就像超人一樣到達
You should have asked.
你應該問
"Do you want to live?"
“你想活著嗎？”
"Should I save your life?"
“我應該救你的命嗎？”
- Like my life's worth anything. - Of course it is.
-就像我的生命有意義一樣-當然有意義
You got married.
你結婚了
Had a beautiful boy. He's in there as we speak.
有了一個漂亮的孩子  我們說話的時候就在那裏
Gave him Sefa as a name. My boy.
給他起名叫做塞法
Then your wife couldn't stand you and ran away.
然後你的妻子受不了你逃跑了
And you started hating all women.
然後你開始討厭所有女人
Your life was fucked. What else could you ask for?
你的生活很糟，你還能要求什麼？
- As though yours wasn't. - We're talking about you for now.
-好像你的不糟  -我們現在說的是你
Don't you have a home or something? Go home.
你冇有家嗎？回家吧
I do.
我有
I do have a home, but there's no one in it.
我有家，但家裏冇有人
You took that one girl home.
你帶那個女孩回了家
We did it on the floor. It doesn't count.
我們是在地闆上做的  那不算
Esin?
內斯林？
What is it, Vural?
什麼事，烏拉爾？
- Blown tyre again? - No, it's not that.
-輪胎又爆了嗎-不是
I was told you were given something for safekeeping.
有人告訴我你有東西要妥善保管
Safekeeping?
保管？
You know how they're tearing the house down?
你知道他們把房子拆掉了嗎？
You took something from the house. What did you take?
你從屋子裏拿走了東西 你拿了什麼？
Have you completely lost it? Is that why you came all the way here?
你有病嗎？這就是為什麼你一路跟到這裏嗎？
Nothing will come out of that house.
房子裏的任何東西都不能帶出來
It's all headed underground.
都要埋到地下
Who says?
誰說的？
Cemil?
塞米爾？
Tell hi to Cemil for me.
給塞米爾問好
Give back what you took and we'll throw it out for you.
把你拿走的東西交出來，我們會為你扔掉
Sadi? What are you doing, son?
薩迪，你在做什麼，孩子？
I'll tell your mom! Give it back!
我要告訴你媽媽！還給我！
- Come on, don't make this any harder. - Vural, stop snooping!
-拜托，別再為難了  -烏拉爾  快停下！
- Stop going through my stuff! - Give back whatever it is you took.
-別再看我的東西了！-把你拿走的東西交出來
You're making a big mistake. Get out of my car!
你犯了個大錯誤  下車！
Auntie, what are you doing? Auntie! Auntie!
阿姨，你在做什麼？阿姨！
Auntie, what are you doing?
阿姨  你在做什麼？
I told you, you were making a big mistake.
我告訴你，你犯了個大錯誤
You're going to break my neck!
你會扭斷我的脖子的！
You'll be just fine. What did I tell you?
你會冇事的  我剛剛不是告訴你了嗎？
- I told you to get lost! - Take it down. I'm begging you!
-我叫你滾蛋！-求求你了，我求求你！
Do you think we're children? Do you think this is all a game?
你認為我們是孩子嗎？你認為這都是遊戲嗎？
- I'm asking you nicely. - You can stop asking.
-我現在很客氣的請求你  -你不用求了
Let's start moving.
我們走吧
- Auntie! Let me go! - You're strangling me!
-阿姨，放開我-你要勒死我了！
- Auntie, let me go! - Auntie, let us go! I'm begging you!
-阿姨，讓我走！-阿姨，讓我們走！求你了！
Bastards!
混蛋！
Now get the fuck out of my face.
現在都他媽給我滾
You'll pay for that, Nesrin. You'll pay for that!
你將為此付出代價，內斯林  你將為此付出代價！
Move, you idiot!
走  白癡！
That's what you get, little shits!
這就是你們的報應，小混蛋！
I must've dozed off, Nesrin.
我一定是打瞌睡了，內斯琳
They're tearing down the house you threw a stone at.
他們把山上的房子拆了
They're leveling it.
夷為平地
It'll all be gone by tomorrow.
明天一切都會消失
But...
但……
Everyone will forget about it anyway.
每個人都會忘記它
I wanted you to know.
我想讓你知道
If, after all these years,
這些年來，如果
your conscience is plaguing you for throwing that stone...
你的良心因你扔石頭睏擾著你……
I went there...
我去了那兒……
And I brought you that stone so that your pain isn't for naught.
我給你帶來了那塊石頭，所以你的痛苦不是毫無意義的
Sleep well.
好好睡
- Cheers. - Cheers.
-幹杯-幹杯
- What brings you here? - I just felt like it.
-什麼風把你刮來了？-我隻是喜歡這裏
Welcome, then.
那就歡迎你
Welcome, but what's wrong with you?
歡迎，但是你怎麼了？
What's right with me, Timur?
帖木兒，我怎麼了？
A psycho killer is out on the loose...
一個變態殺手在逃
And here I am enjoying myself, having raki with you.
而我在這裏和葡萄酒
- Let's enjoy ourselves, then. - Let's.
-盡情享受吧  -享受吧
Do you still think about Nevra?
你還想內芙拉嗎？
No.
冇有
It's over.
結束了
- Sure. If you say so. - It is.
-當然  如果你這樣說  -是的
It was a childish fantasy. It's over. I mean...
那是一個孩子氣的幻想  已經結束了  我是說……
I was kidding myself.
我是在逗自己玩
I thought there was something, but it was a mistake.
我以為有什麼感覺，但那是個錯誤
Officer Nevra's world has no place in it for me.
內芙拉警官的世界冇有我的位置
Plus, look what happened. Look who she's with now.
另外，看看發生了什麼  看看她現在和誰在一起
So what? Was your crazy Ceyda any better?
那又怎樣？你那個瘋狂的傑伊達好點了嗎？
Getting a divorce from her wasn't fun, was it?
和她離婚不好玩，對吧?
You're right.
是的
Never mind all that. How are the kids doing?
冇關係，孩子們過得怎麼樣？
Good. They're doing good.
好  他們過得不錯
They start running away whenever they see me. But they're good.
他們一見到他們就躲開，但是他們很好
Timur...
帖木兒
- I'm going to give my resignation. - What are you talking about?
-我要辭職了 -你在說什麼？
If I can't catch this guy, I shouldn't be in this line of business.
如果我不能抓住這個人，我就不應該從事這個行業
If I can't catch him, they'll take her away anyway.
如果我抓不到兇手，他們會把她帶走的
Thanks.
謝謝
I couldn't bear that.
我不能忍受
Tolga... Let me to tell you something.
托爾加  讓我告訴你一些事
You remember when you told me
你記得你告訴過我
that Nevra wanted to give her resignation but you refused?
內芙拉想辭職，但你拒絕了？
I'm refusing yours, brother.
我拒絕你  兄弟
I'm refusing your letter of resignation.
我拒絕你的辭呈
You're going to find that bastard.
你一定能抓到兇手
And then, you're going to put him behind bars.
然後，你要把他關在牢裏
- You got that? - Got it, Chief.
-你明白了嗎  -知道了
You know what I want to do? I want to go on a vacation with you.
你知道我想做什麼嗎？我想和你一起度假
Just for two-three days. What do you say?
就兩三天，你覺得怎麼樣？
I don't know. There's Zuhal and Deva. Things come up.
不好說啊  祖哈爾和德瓦怎麼辦
They can take care of themselves. What do you say? Let's go.
他們可以照顧自己的  你覺得怎麼樣？我們一起去吧
I don't know.
我不知道
- There's nothing to know. - Can I ask you something?
-冇什麼可知道的  -我能問你一件事嗎？
You know how you told me your husband...
你知道你是怎麼告訴我你丈夫……
That your departed husband was in an accident?
你丈夫因意外過身的嗎？
Can we not talk about that right now?
我們現在能不談論這個嗎？
I just want to ask something.
我隻想問一點
You can ask if you promise to come on a vacation with me.
如果你答應和我去度假的話我就讓你問
Alright.
好的
You know how he caused the accident because he wanted to die?
你知道他造成了意外是因為他想死
What do you think would happen if he'd failed
你認為如果他在事故中自殺
to kill himself with that accident?
失敗了會怎麼樣？
I can answer that right away. He'd die again and again every day.
我可以馬上回答你  他會每天都嘗試去死
Every day for the rest of his life.
終生的每一天
I see.
我懂了
Why do you ask?
你為什麼要問？
I made a decision today.
我今天做了個決定
I was wondering if I made the right one.
我想知道我做的是否正確
That's why I asked.
這就是為什麼我問
- What was this decision? - I want to tell you something.
-這個決定是什麼？-我想告訴你一些事情
And the only one I've shared it with so far is my cat.
到目前為止，我唯一與之分享的是我的貓
Now I'm sharing it with you.
現在我要和你分享
I'm really scared of death.
我真的很怕死
- Everyone is. - Sure. I know that.
-每個人都是  -當然，我知道
Today, I decided what to do with that fear.
今天，我決定如何應對這種恐懼
I told you I was at a funeral today.
我和你說過我今天在葬禮上
I kicked a ball around with some kids in the courtyard of the mosque.
我和幾個孩子在清真寺的院子裏踢球
Something happened then.
然後有事發生了
I felt something.
我感覺到了什麼
I said to myself: "Agah, don't be scared of being afraid."
我對自己說：“阿加，別因害怕而感到害怕”
"Instead of fearing death and dying every day,
“與其每天害怕死亡
fear death, sure, but live every day."
不如活好每一天”
How's that?
怎麼樣？
- Beautiful. - Beautiful.
-說得好  -說得好
To health.
敬健康
Drop the phone please.
請放下手機
You've been staring at it since you walked in.
你來了之後就一直盯著它
Nobody called.
冇有人打電話
What did you expect? She's kept quiet for ten years.
你有什麼期望？她已經沈默了十年
Would she break her silence because you came along?
因為你來了，她就會打破沈默嗎？
Give it some time. Be patient.
給她一點時間  耐心點
Think how hard it must be for her.
想想對她來說有多難
You're right.
你是對的
You're right. What are you doing?
你是對的，你在做什麼？
Creating a media empire for myself.
為自己打造一個媒體帝國
I'm starting a Youtube channel.
我正在創建一個YouTube頻道
- Unknown caller. - Answer it. Go on, answer it.
-未知來電  -接啊，快接
Hello?
餵？
Yes, this is her. I don't...
是的，是我，我……
Miss, please calm down.  Please stop shouting. I'm listening.
小姐  請冷靜點  不要喊  我在聽
What?
什麼？
Can you tell me who did it?
你能告訴我是誰做的嗎？
Alright.
好的
Can we meet? It will...
我們可以見麵嗎？
It will take me some time to drive to Kambura from Istanbul.
從伊斯坦佈爾開車到坎佈拉需要一些時間
Is that so?
是嗎？
Alright.
好的
Yes. Alright. I'm on my way.
好的，我現在過去
She talked about a rape.
她談到強奸
Tayyar Kaymak.
塔亞爾·凱馬克
- I'm going. - You're going now?
-我要走了 -現在嗎？
Where is she?
她在哪？
- Have you been waiting long? - It's alright, it's just that...
-等了很久嗎？ -冇事  隻是……
The station was really crowded.
車站真的很擠
So many buildings. All on top of each other.
如此多的建築物相互重疊
How do you live here?
你在這裏怎麼生活？
It's pretty hard, to be honest.
老實說這很難
Yeliz...
耶利茲
- Can I call you Yeliz? - Yes, yes, of course.
-我可以叫給你耶利茲嗎-當然可以
- You can call me Nevra. - Alright.
-你可以叫我內芙拉-好的
Were you already going to come here? Do you have relatives here or something?
你本來就準備來這裏嗎？你在這裏有親戚嗎？
No. When I told him I was going to talk to you,
當我告訴他我要和你談的時候，
my husband kicked me out of the house.
我丈夫把我踢出了家門
I see.
我懂了
- Do you have children? - No. We couldn't have children.
-你有孩子嗎？-不，我們冇辦法懷孩子
Alright. Here's what we're going to do.
好了  這就是我們要做的
Come in.
進來吧
This way.
這邊
- May I? - Go on. Make yourself at home.
-可以嗎？-來吧  像在家裏一樣
You can stay here for the night. We'll figure it out tomorrow.
你可以在這裏過夜  我們明天會解決的
Go on. Make yourself at home.
來吧  就像在自己家一樣
- Hello? - Hello?
-餵？-餵？
Hello? Nevra? I was worried. You weren't answering your phone.
餵？內芙拉？我很擔心  你冇有接電話
We just got home.
我們剛到家
She's staying at my place for the night.
她在我家過夜
She doesn't have anyone to turn to.
他們有任何人可以投靠
Sure. Alright, we can talk later.
當然可以，我們稍後再談
It's not very comfortable, but it's better than nothing.
雖然不是很舒服，但總比冇有好
It's no trouble at all. Thank you.
冇關係  謝謝
Nevra...
內芙拉
I didn't know anything. I was completely unaware.
我什麼都不知道  我完全不知道
I don't get it. Unaware of what?
我不明白  不知道什麼？
Ufuk didn't tell me anything.
烏福克什麼都冇告訴我
He didn't tell me he was going to burn the house down.
他冇有告訴我他要把房子燒掉
He never used to talk, anyway. He was strange. He kept to himself.
總之他以前很少說話，他很奇怪  很自閉
He got much stranger after the fire.
大火過後他變得很陌生
How could I have known he would've burned that house down?
我怎麼知道他會把那所房子燒掉？
That the whole family inside would perish in the fire?
他的家人都在大火中喪生嗎？
- It was all my fault. - Come on. Take a seat.
-都是我的錯  -來吧  坐下說
It's all my fault.
都是我的錯
All those children died because of me. I can't bear it.
所有那些孩子都死了，都是因為我，我受不了了
Calm down. Please calm down. Let's wipe your face.
冷靜點  請冷靜下來  先擦擦眼淚吧
Calm down.
冷靜
Can you tell me everything from the start?
你能從頭講起嗎？
I hadn't gotten married yet.
我那時還冇結婚
I was my father's dear girl. He couldn't bear to see me get married.
我是我父親的寶貝女兒  他不忍心看到我結婚
- Is he still alive? - No. He passed away.
-他還活著嗎？-不，他過世了
- My condolences. - Thank you.
-節哀  -謝謝
I was on my way home from the grocer's. He appeared out of nowhere. Tayyar.
我正從雜貨店回家的路上  塔亞爾突然出現
He grabbed me by the arm. Before I knew what was going on,
他抓住我的手臂  在我還冇搞清楚情況之前
he took me aside and put a knife against my throat.
他把我拉到一邊，用刀對著我的喉嚨
Then he...
然後他……
In the trees by my place...
在我家旁邊的樹林裏……
- Did something like that happen again? - Yes.
-之後這種事情又發生了嗎？-是的
He told me that if I said anything to anyone he'd humiliate me.
他告訴我，如果我對任何人說起，他就會羞辱我
How could I tell anyone? My father was sick.
我怎麼能告訴別人？  當時我父親病了
And my mom? What was I supposed to tell her?
還有我媽媽  我該怎麼開口？
- So you didn't tell anyone anything. - No one.
-所以你冇跟任何人說-冇有
How did Ufuk find out?
烏福克是怎麼發現的？
Tayyar brought Ufuk along one day.
有一天塔亞爾把烏福克帶來了
Told me to bed him, as well.
讓我也跟他睡
Why would he do that?
他為什麼要那樣做？
He tricked Ufuk. Took his money. Then told him about this girl.
他騙了烏福克  拿了他的錢  然後告訴他這有個妓女
He brought Ufuk along, but he ran away when he saw me.
他帶來了烏福克，但是烏福克見到我就逃走了
He couldn't stomach it. When he realized that I was the girl...
當他意識到我就是那個妓女時，他受不了了
He ran away. He loved me, but I didn't know. That's why he ran.
他逃跑了  他愛我，但我當時不知道那是他逃跑的原因
I realized it too late. The next day, he found me.
我很久以後才知道  第二天，烏福克來找我
Told me not to worry, that he'd handle everything.
告訴我不要擔心，他會處理一切
I asked him what he meant.
我問他是什麼意思
Then, a week later or so...
然後，大約一周後……
Yes, it was a week later. One night...
是的，這是一周後的一個晚上……
There were these shouts.
喊叫聲此起彼伏
Next thing we knew,
接下來人們就知道了
he'd burned the place down.
他把那房子燒了
It was already too late.
已經太晚了
After all that, Ufuk found me again. Told me he'd handled it.
在那之後烏福克又來找過我  說他已經都處理好了
After that day, he never spoke to me again.
那天過後，他再也冇有跟我說話
I see.
我懂了
Halis...
哈裏斯……
Did you know Halis?
你認識哈裏斯嗎？
Halis?
哈裏斯？
Fireman.
消防員
Oh, Halis. Yes, I knew him. He passed.
哦，哈裏斯，我知道他，他過身了
He put it in his report that a cigarette butt started the fire.
他在報告中說是煙頭引起了火災
Why would he do that? Why would he protect Ufuk?
他為什麼要這樣做？為什麼要保護烏福克？
Why would he hide the fact that Ufuk started the fire?
他為什麼會掩蓋烏福克縱火的事實？
There was this judge.
有這麼一個法官
- Mehmet something? - Mehmet Yurtgil.
-穆罕默德 什麼的？-穆罕默德·尤爾吉爾
- I don't know his surname. - Mehmet Yurtgil.
-我不知道他的姓氏-穆罕默德·尤爾吉爾
He came and found me. Told me...
他來找我  告訴我……
I wasn't to tell anyone anything.
我冇有告訴過任何人
He told me that the family that died was Romani.
他告訴我，死去的一家人是吉普賽人
If it was heard that a Romani family was burned alive in Kambura,
如果別人聽說有一家吉普賽人在坎佈拉被活活燒死，
no one would care that they were targeted because of me.
冇有人會擔心他們是因我而死的
Everyone would assume that they were targeted because of their ethnicity.
所有人都會認為他們的死因是種族
That's what he said.
那就是他跟我說的
Some people had forcibly kicked a Romani family out of Kambura.
有人強行將吉普賽一家人趕出坎佈拉
He didn't want Kambura to get a bad rap,
他不想讓坎佈拉名聲掃地
so he told me not to say anything. So I said yes.
他告訴我什麼都不要說  所以我答應了他
The judge must've spoken to Halis. That's why he said it was a cigarette.
法官一定對哈裏斯說過什麼，這就是為什麼他說是煙頭引發的火災
What else could he have done? Kambura would've gotten a bad rap.
他還能做什麼？會有損坎佈拉的名譽
Alright.
好的
You rest for now. We can talk again in the morning. OK?
你先休息吧，我們明天早上再談  可以嗎？
Sure. But I've told you everything.
當然可以，但我已經告訴過你一切
What else is there to talk about?
還有什麼要談的？
I don't know anything else.
其他的我什麼都不知道
Good morning.
早上好
How are you feeling? Did you sleep well?
感覺怎麼樣？睡得好嗎？
Yes. I slept alright.
是的，我睡得很好
Thanks.
謝謝
Nevra, can you drop me off at the station today?
內芙拉，你今天可以載我去車站嗎？
Of course. Are you going back to Kambura?
當然可以  你要回坎佈拉嗎？
No.
不是
I'm not going back there again.
我不會再回去了
I'm going to go to Bursa. I have relatives there.
我要去佈爾薩  那裏有親戚
I see.
明白
Yeliz, I need to ask you something.
葉莉茲  我要問你一件事
The things you told me last night...
你昨晚告訴我的事情……
There's nothing I can do about them as a cop.
作為警察我無能為力
All the people you mentioned are already dead.
你提到的所有人都已經死了
I don't get it.
我不明白
Why did you run from home? Did you come here just to tell me this?
你為什麼要從家裏跑出來？你來這裏隻是為了告訴我嗎？
You know why?
你知道為什麼嗎？
I needed to get it off my chest so much.
我需要把這些話說出來
I've kept quiet for years and years.
我多年來一直保持沈默
And after I got married? Forget about it.
結婚之後
My husband figured it out.
我丈夫發現了
When it was time to have sex, he checked and saw that I was a woman.
到了做愛的時候，他檢查了一下，發現我不是處女
Well...
好吧……
I thought he'd kick me out then.
我以為他會把我趕出去
I thought he'd leave me. But he really loved me.
我以為他會離開我  但他是真的愛我
He loved me so much. He told me not to explain.
他太愛我了  他告訴我不用解釋
"No matter what you did, don't tell me, I don't want to know about it," he said.
他說：“不管你做過什麼，都不要告訴我，我也不想知道  ”
So I kept quiet.
所以我保持沈默
Then, when we couldn't have children, it was his turn to keep quiet.
然後，當我們發現不能有孩子時，輪到他保持沈默了
We kept quiet. Husband and wife. Our whole lives.
我們保持沈默的夫妻生活
Keeping a secret makes you feel like you're in prison.
保守秘密會讓你覺得自己像是在監獄裏
I wanted to get it off my chest. I wanted to get it out of me.
我想把這些話說出來  甩開它
I wanted to finally breathe and be free.
我想自由的呼吸
I hoped it might do some good.
我希望這樣可能會有所幫助
But...
但……
You say there's nothing you can do.
你說你無能為力
I'm sorry. I took so much of your time.
對不起，我佔用了你很長時間
I've kept you off more urgent business. I'm really sorry. Please forgive me.
我讓你錯過了更緊急的事情  我真的很抱歉，請原諒
Don't be silly. That's not what I meant.
別傻了  我不是那個意思
I'm glad that you came. I'm glad that you told me all that.
我很高興你來了  我很高興你你把這些事情告訴我
Thanks.
謝謝
Thank you for listening to me.
謝謝你聽我說
- Have something to eat. - Alright.
-吃點東西-好的
Well, how was our day?
好了，我們今天過得怎麼樣？
Good. So you liked the tour.
好，所以你喜歡這次旅行
Great. We'll do it again. We certainly will. Don't worry.
太好了  我們再做一次  當然會的  別擔心
Feza. Feza.
費紮
Feza. Feza?
費紮？
We'll do it again...
我們會再做一次
We'll arrange good tours.
我們會安排好旅行
Everything was perfect...
一切都很完美
I'm so glad to hear that.
我很高興聽到這個消息
Feza. Feza.
費紮
This way...
這邊……
Call if you need anything, alright?
如有需要，打個電話好嗎？
Sure. Of course. Thank you so much.
當然可以，非常感謝
You don't have to wait for the bus to leave.
你不必等著車開走
- Have a good journey. - Thank you. Thank you so much.
-旅途愉快  -謝謝  非常感謝你
- Don't. - You aren't checking it?
-不用  -你不坐車了嗎？
No.
不
I hate buses. You should skip it, as well.
我討厭公共汽車  你也別坐了
So, Feza... How about another journey?
那麼，費紮  我們去另一個旅行怎麼樣？
How about another poem?
另外一首詩？
Hello
餵？
Yes.
是
是的
Feza. Come on. We're here.
來吧  費紮  我們到了
Come on.
來吧
It's right there. Just a short walk away. Go on.
就在那兒  幾步之遙  加油
This way, Feza. This way.
這邊  費紮
Feza? This way.
費紮？這邊
This way, Feza.
這邊
We're almost there. After these stairs...
就快到了  過了這幾個臺階……
We'll turn left, and then...
我們嚮左轉，然後……
Feza, forgive me. I know it was quite a walk.
費紮，原諒我，我知道那是很長的一段路
But the elevator's always broken.
但是電梯總是壞
Always broken. I don't know why.
總是壞  我不知道為什麼
Why won't it go in?
為什麼不進去呢？
They won't be home.
他們不會回來的
The kids are both out. Don't ring the bell.
孩子們都出去了  別按門鈴
Don't ring the bell. There's nobody home.
別按門鈴  冇有人在家
Feza, there's nobody home. Stop ringing the bell. That's enough.
費紮，冇有人在家  別按門鈴！
Yes?
誰啊？
Nezaket?
內紮凱特 ？
It's Agah.
我是阿加
Speak louder. I can't hear you.
大聲說  我聽不到你的聲音
Agah.
阿加
Do you remember me?
你還記得我嗎？
I used to live here with my wife, Mebrure.
我曾經和我的妻子梅佈魯雷一起住在這裏
You were our landlord. Agah Beyoglu.
你是我們的房東  我是阿加·貝尤魯
Agah Beyoglu.
阿加·貝尤魯
Agah!
阿加！
Come on in. Come in.
進來進來
So, Agah... You wanted to see your old home?
那麼，阿加  你是想看看你的老房子嗎？
I understand. It must be full of memories.
我能理解  這裏一定充滿回憶的
We used to live upstairs, as you know.
如你所知，我們曾經住在樓上
When Fikri died, I took a good look around.
菲克裏過身後，我環顧四周
Living on my own in a huge apartment wasn't going to work out.
我自己住在一個巨大的公寓裏不行的
So I came down here.
所以我搬下來了
Tell you what.
告訴你吧
Do you remember Iclal? My daughter?
你還記得伊克拉爾嗎？我的女兒？
She got married and moved to Ankara.
她結婚後搬到了安卡拉
She never calls me anymore.
她再也冇有打電話給我
Why would someone neglect their own mother so much?
為什麼會有人這麼對待自己的母親？
Here's how it goes.
這是怎麼回事
I call her, she yawns and yawns on the other end.
我打電話給她，她不停的打哈欠
When I ask what's wrong, she tells me she's getting sleepy.
當我問出什麼問題時，她告訴我她很睏
It baffles me.
這讓我感到睏惑
When she was a little girl...
當她還是一個小女孩時
I'd swing her for hours, but she wouldn't get a wink of sleep.
我要把她搖搖晃晃幾個小時，但她一點都不睏
Now, whenever I call to talk, she yawns and yawns.
現在，每當我打電話時，她都會哈欠
When I ask what's wrong, she tells me she's getting sleepy.
當我問出什麼問題時，她告訴我她很睏
So I stopped calling. What else was I supposed to do?
所以我不再打電話給她  我該怎麼辦？
I had to accept it.
我不得不接受
So?
那麼？
Where do you live now, Agah?
阿加，你現在住在哪裏？
Where do you live?
你住在哪裏？
- That's what I'm trying to remember. - What's that supposed to mean?
-這就是我試圖記起來的  -什麼意思？
Don't you know where you live? Where your home is?
你不知道你住在哪裏嗎？你家在哪裏？
- What's Mebrure saying? - That's not Mebrure.
-梅佈魯雷在說什麼？-她不是梅佈魯雷
- Excuse me? - That's not Mebrure!
-什麼？-她不是梅佈魯雷！
I'm asking myself a different question. Why did I come here?
我在問自己一個不同的問題  我為什麼要來這裏？
Might I have come here to kill you?
我可能會來這裏殺死你嗎？
What are you saying? I can't hear you. Speak louder.
你在說什麼  我聽不到你  大點聲
Nezaket, have you ever been to Kambura?
內紮凱特，你去過坎佈拉嗎？
- What? - Kambura!
-什麼？-坎佈拉！
Have you ever been to Kambura?
你去過坎佈拉嗎？
You're losing it.
你瘋了
Get off it!
別胡扯！
DOG SLAYER
狗殺手